Bridges carry cities every day — and when one fails,
the cost is measured in lives, not dollars.
As more of the world's bridges age past their prime,
the hardest question in infrastructure safety is deceptively simple: how do you catch
a structure's quiet, invisible changes before visible damage ever appears?
Traditional monitoring struggles with exactly this — sparse sensors leave blind spots,
and even where fiber-optic sensing gives full coverage, the raw data floods in
faster than any engineer can read it by hand.
This is MurSense: an AI agent that lets anyone ask,
in plain language, how a bridge is doing right now —
and get back an answer grounded in real, validated engineering analysis,
not a guess.
Under the hood, an AI agent reads the question and routes it to
one of three core capabilities — vibration analysis, health diagnosis,
or knowledge Q&A — then hands the actual computation to a validated,
deterministic algorithm engine: power-spectral-density analysis, modal-frequency extraction, five-level alert scoring.
Every number it returns comes from that engine, run on real DAS fiber-optic
sensing data — 100 Hz sampling, 1,034 channels — never invented by the
AI itself.
Let's log in.
This is MurSense's main workspace: a sidebar for conversation history and saved projects,
a top bar for language and theme, and a center panel that starts
every session with one simple question — what would you like to know
about bridge health?
One click switches the whole interface to a dark theme —
same layout, easier on the eyes for a night shift.
The interface itself is fully trilingual — Chinese, English, French —
switching instantly, no reload.
Even the assistant's own name changes with the language.
Expand "More" and you'll see MurSense's full capability set laid out as one-click
examples: vibration analysis, spectral diagnostics, knowledge Q&A, report generation.
There's even a fifth card for load identification — clearly marked as a
planned direction, not something we're claiming works today.
The user guide walks a first-time visitor through exactly how to talk to
the assistant — say a date, say "analyze", say "export a report" —
and shows the real scale of the data underneath: 100 hertz sampling,
1,034 channels, continuously.
At any point you can pick a specific data file from this dropdown
— MurSense fills in the right analysis prompt automatically.
Now the core of the product.
Ask, in plain language, how the bridge is doing today.
Watch the status line — the assistant is routing this to a real
analysis tool, not just chatting.
Moments later: a complete health assessment.
At the top, the exact tool that ran — check_bridge_health —
so you know this came from validated code, not a guess.
Below it, the scalar metrics: strain and modal frequency, both compared against baseline.
And here's the nuance a real system produces that a mockup wouldn't:
the scalar averages look perfectly normal, but the spatial breakdown flags a localized
anomaly — an orange-level warning at a specific stretch of the bridge,
with a clear recommendation attached.
Ask for the power spectrum on a specific channel, and MurSense draws it
live — this is channel 519's real frequency curve, with four modal frequencies
automatically picked out and labeled in hertz.
Zoom back out to the full picture: a waterfall plot across all 1,034
channels, showing exactly where each resonant frequency runs consistently —
or doesn't.
MurSense isn't limited to running numbers — ask it a domain question directly,
like how to read an anomaly in this plot, and it retrieves from
its own knowledge base and walks you through an actual diagnostic decision tree.
Every answer carries the same footer: which model answered, how many tokens it
used, how long it took — and three one-click actions:
copy, export, save.
Export turns any analysis into a formatted Word report in one click —
tables, figures, and all — ready to hand to a bridge owner.
Save archives the same analysis into a named project, so nothing gets lost
between sessions.
That saved report shows up immediately in Projects — title,
word count, figure count, health level, all at a glance.
Open any archived report and you get a full editor:
Markdown on the left, a live preview on the right,
and a one-click export to a standalone HTML file you can share with
anyone.
The Data Space is where the raw material lives: your own uploaded recordings,
with a live multi-channel waveform preview you can inspect channel by channel —
pick specific channels to compare and adjust their spacing for a clearer view
— before ever running an analysis.
There's also a shared public demo dataset, and an organization-shared tier gated to
enterprise accounts.
Click analyze on any file here, and MurSense jumps straight back to the
chat with the right prompt already filled in.
The account pages round out the basics: profile, real usage statistics,
a push-notification setup reserved for the cloud-deployed tier, and password management.
System settings let you point MurSense at your own LLM provider and API
key, set a preferred reply language, and switch the whole interface's language —
all without restarting anything.
And a direct feedback channel, straight to the developer.
One rule keeps all of this trustworthy: the AI never writes analysis code
on the fly, and it never sees the raw waveform data directly.
A validated algorithm package does the actual computation; the model only decides which
tool to call and explains the result.
MurSense: real sensors, real analysis, and an assistant that shows its work.